大家好 我是Sheldon Cooper博士
Hello, I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
我是Amy Farrah Fowler博士
And I'm Dr. Amy Farrah Fowler.
欢迎来到第一期"实景拍摄"的
And welcome to the first "on location" episode of
由Sheldon Cooper博士和Amy Farrah Fowler博士共同为你带来的
Dr. Sheldon Cooper and Dr. Amy Farrah Fowler present:
Sheldon Cooper博士的旗乐无穷
Dr. Sheldon Cooper's Fun with Flags.
音乐走起
Hit it.
# 为了愉悦和开心 #
# For joy and fun #
# 没有什么更好的方法 #
# There's no better manner #
# 除了让三角旗飞扬 #
# Than to fly a pennant #
# 普通旗子或横幅迎风招展 #
# Flag or banner #
# 填充了我内心 #
# What fills my heart #
# 使我眼里常含泪水的 #
# And makes my eyes moist #
# 就是把旗子 #
# Sending a flag #
# 高高地升上旗杆顶端 #
# Up a pole on a hoist #
# 旗乐无穷 #
# Fun with flags #
# 哦! 你看得到吗 #
# Oh! Say can you see #
# 这就是旗乐无穷 #
# It's fun with flags #
# 旗乐无穷 #
# Fun with flags. #
你们也看到了 节目众多改变之一就是
As you may notice, just one of the changes around here
有了我们的专属乐队
is our new house band.
还想跟我们抢镜头呢
Who haven't learned their place yet.
改变之二就是 我们换了个直播地点
We're also coming to you live from a different apartment.
Fowler博士和我开始了同居实验
Dr. Fowler and I began an experiment in living together
因为她的公寓被水淹了
after her apartment became water damaged.
这是我们的朋友Penny家
This is our friend Penny's place.
你们可能在"旗子"或者
You may remember her from our episode "Flags".
"不了解它们的人"这两期节目中听说过她
And "The People Who Don't Understand Them."
本着同居的精神
So, in the spirit of cohabitation,
今天这期节目的主题就是两个地区的旗子
the theme of today's episode is flags of two regions
组合成了一个的故事
coming together as one.
比如圣基茨和尼维斯
Such as the flag of St. Kitts and Nevis.
所以 我们卷起袖子来了解下尼维斯吧
So, let's roll up our "sleevis" and get to know Nevis.
我喜欢这个 不过下次跟我说一声
Well, I-I like that, but next time check with me.
你知道这个旗子是
Did you know that the flag
一个名叫Edrice Lewis的学生设计的吗...
was designed by a student named Edrice Lewis...
真不敢相信我会说这种话 不过我们不能看看新闻
I can't believe I'm saying this, but can we watch the news
什么的吗?
or something?
很好啊 他们同居得很开心
It's cute, they're having fun living together.
是啊 我在想她公寓修好之后
Yeah, I wonder what they're gonna do
他们要怎么办
when her apartment's ready.
其实 好几个星期前就修好了
Actually, it's been ready for weeks.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
他们早完工了
Well, they finished the work early,
但她一直和Sheldon说他们工期延误了
but she's been telling Sheldon they're behind schedule.
所以 她就这么一直骗他吗?
So, she's just been lying to him?
你也骗过Sheldon啊
Well, you've lied to Sheldon.
对啊 但我是想让他离开
Yeah, but to make him leave,
不是想留下他
not to make him stay.
布达和佩斯联合在一起组成了布达佩斯
Buda and Pest united to form Budapest.
这就是为什么布达佩斯
And that's why Budapest
是"布达倍儿棒"
"Budabest."
就是现在
Now.
哦 好吧
Oh, right.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall * * We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第十季第3集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥累成渣渣
校对: UU跪求运气
翻译: 肉肉君 六遇 李小宝Licht 言小默
谢谢你们的服务 先生们
Thank you for your services, gentlemen.
现在我希望
Now, I'm hoping
用你们的摇滚乐
to broaden our audience
增加一些观众
with your youthful rock and roll music.
你居然认为你有观众 真是好笑
You think you have an audience, that's funny.
我们拿不到工钱吗? 什么都没有?
We don't get paid? Nothing?
三明治都没有?
Not even a sandwich?
都快晚饭时间了
It's almost dinner time.
你想吃什么吗?
You in the mood for anything?
我们可以去你家附近吃泰国菜
Yeah, we could get Thai food near your apartment
然后顺路进去看一下进度
and then drop in and check on the progress.
你不会想去看它的 那是施工区
Oh, you don't want do that, it's a construction zone.
那又怎样?
So?
你对到处乱丢的钉子和屁股沟的恐惧呢?
Well, what about your fear of stray nails and butt cracks?
我很害怕踩到钉子上
I am terrified of stepping on a nail
还有掉进屁股沟里
and falling into a butt crack.
随便吧 晚饭怎么办?
Anyway, how about dinner?
你知道吧 如果你想要的话 我可以
You know, if you'd like, I could
打电话给房东投诉这个
call your landlord and complain.
谢谢 但是你没有必要
Thanks, but you don't have to.
我不介意啊 我很擅长投诉的
Oh, I don't mind, I'm very good at complaining.
如果是奥运体育项目的话 我会投诉
If it were an Olympic sport, I'd complain about
这个运动有多么蠢然后自己把金牌带回家
what a stupid sport it is and then I'd take home the gold.
说得好
Good stuff.
所以 晚上吃什么?
So, uh, what about dinner?
是我想多了
Is it me
还是你总是在故意换话题?
or are you purposely changing the subject?
没有
No.
当说到话题这个话题时
And on the subject of subjects,
你用的"话题"这个词和我们讨论
is your use of the word "subject" the same or different
subject既有话题也有臣民的意思
国王的臣民时意义一样吗?
as when we speak about the subject of a king?
我感觉你还是在换话题
I have a feeling you're still doing it.
但我感觉这个话题不能抵制
But I find that topic irresistible, so,
现在 在古美索不达米亚
now, in ancient Mesopotamia,
国王把他的臣民视为他自己的财产
the king referred to the people as his property.
我是认真的
I'm serious,
喷气推进实验室已经在开发一种
JPL's actually developing a robot arm
可以在小行星撞击地球之前抓住它的机械臂了
that could grab an asteroid before it hits us.
所以他们把地球从世界末日拯救出来的计划就是
So their plan for saving the Earth from Armageddon
寄希望于一群科学家来抓个球?
is hoping a bunch of scientists can catch a ball?
如果我们都要死 我还吃这么多羽衣甘蓝干什么?
If we're all gonna die, why am I eating so much kale?
你今天这么安静 还好吗?
You're awful quiet, everything okay?
我很担心Amy
I'm concerned about Amy.
最近她表现地很奇怪
She's acting a bit odd lately.
我就是好奇下
Oh. Well, j-just out of curiosity,
什么在你看来是奇怪的?
what registers as odd to you?
她的行为
Her behavior.
我总觉得她瞒着我一些事情
No, I have the feeling that she's hiding something.
没必要这么担心
I wouldn't worry about it.
她可能只是因为工作上的事情觉得困扰罢了
She's probably just distracted by work.
不管是什么吧 我觉得很困扰
Well, whatever it is, it's troubling me.
饭也吃不下 觉也睡不着
And I can't eat, I can't sleep.
更不用说肠胃蠕动的
And don't even ask about the consistency
规律性了
of my bowel movements.
听到了吧 别多嘴瞎问
You heard him, guys, don't ask.
她为什么要对我遮遮掩掩的呢?
Why would she keep something from me, you know?
宝宝可是把处子之身都给她了
I shared my body with that woman.
还有我Netflix的密码
And my Netflix password.
网站还自动推荐了当老牛碰上嫩草
They recommended Stella Got Her Groove Back
就是她看多了
because of her.
兄弟 听我说
Buddy, buddy, listen,
没什么大不了的事情
nothing bad is going on,
她只是... 她只是不想你知道
she just... she just didn't want you to know
她公寓那里的修理工程几星期之前就完成了
that the work on her apartment was finished a couple weeks ago.
我不明白你的意思
I don't understand.
她享受和你同居的时光
She's enjoying living with you
不希望就这样早早结束了
and she didn't want it to end early.
所以她欺骗了我
So, she's deceiving me
就是为了多和我呆在一起
in order to spend more time with me.
是的
Yes. Oh.
我真是受宠若惊又伤心欲绝啊
Well, I feel both flattered and hurt.
就像别人说我长得像圣诞惊魂夜里的
Like when people say I look like that skeleton
那个骷髅头一样
from Nightmare Before Christmas.
我的天呐 真是描绘得出神入化
Oh my God, that's who you look like.
Sheldon 这没什么大不了的
Sheldon, this is not a big deal.
这是个善意的谎言 我们都说过
It's a little white lie, everyone does it.
我没说过
Not me,
我在我的所有关系当中
I'm a 100% honest
都是百分百坦诚的
in all of my relationships.
所以看看你现在形单影只的可怜样儿
And how single are you right now?
一个人坐在马桶上吃蛋糕的痛
Eating-cake-on-the-toilet single.
我绝不能容忍情感里的欺骗
Well, I won't tolerate deception in my relationship.
除了和她当面对质 我别无选择
I have no choice but to confront her.
别这么做 你现在可是把柄在手
Don't do that, you've got gold here.
好好抓住了 等到你遇到麻烦的时候
Hang onto it until you're in trouble
就可以... 打她个措手不及
and then... throw it in her face.
什么?
What?
你为什么要告诉他这个?
Why would you tell him that?
这个建议烂透了
That's terrible advice.
所以你不希望抓到Penny的任何把柄咯?
So you wouldn't want to have anything on Penny?
当然不希望
Well, of course not.
所以 如果我现在真的知道一些内幕的话...
So, if I actually know something right now...
实际上我真的知道...
and I do...
你不希望我告诉你吗?
you don't want me to tell you?
这个嘛...
Uh...
当然不了
Pfft, no.
你这态度真是一个大写的"要"啊
I'll take that as a "Yes."
她一直在悄悄把你的收藏品搬到仓库去
She's secretly been moving your collectibles into storage
一次一点点 这样你就不会注意到了
a little at a time and you haven't noticed.
你说真的吗?
Are you kidding me?
看吧 我已经知道很久了
See, I've known that for weeks,
但我就等啊等啊
but, you know, I waited till the moment
等到对他的伤害达到最大值的时候再说
when it would cause him the most pain.
超人不见了 我的暴风兵也不见了
Superman's gone, my stormtrooper's gone.
你的克林贡版每日一次的日历也不见了
Your Klingon word-of-the-day calendar's gone.
我想用克林贡语骂"我去"
I'd say "damn it" in Klingon,
但那个词要到下个月才会学到
but that wasn't until next month.
来 跟我说 "窝趣"
It's "khoo-vakh."
窝趣!
Khoo-vakh!
连我的Waldo藏在哪儿都被她拿走了
She took my Where's Waldo.
没 没 他在那儿呢
Well, no, no, he's over there.
哦 原来在这儿啊
Oh, yeah, there he is.
你的公寓怎么样了?
So, what's the deal with your apartment?
怎么修了这么久啊?
Why's it taking so long?
是干式墙出了问题
Um, it was a drywall problem.
不会吧 出了什么事?
Oh, no, what happened?
就是干式墙湿了  没人想要湿了的干式墙是不是
Well, the drywall got wet, and you do not want wet drywall
因为干式墙湿了的时候 就变成了...
because when drywall gets wet, it's really more...
湿式墙?
Wet wall?
说潮墙也行 都差不多
Or damp wall, just as bad. Mm.
那他们怎么不多买点干式墙呢?
So why don't they just get more drywall?
他们去买了的
Well, they went to get some,
但是墙面专卖店的人说
but the woman at the wall store
干式墙最近热销 所以他们要等着
said it was going on sale and they should wait
因为库存... 真是够了 你说完了吗?
because the savings... Okay, are you done?
Bernadette告诉我你的公寓已经修好了
Bernadette told me your apartment's ready.
我说到湿式墙的时候就打算停了 但你一直抓着不放
I was done at wet wall, but you wouldn't let it go.
但Sheldon真的信了这些鬼话吗?
But is Sheldon really believing all this crap?
他确实开始怀疑了 但我假装对着他打了个喷嚏
Well, he started to question it, but then I fake sneezed on him
之后他就去洗澡了
and he ran to take a shower.
你千万要帮我保密 我已经够挣扎的了
Please don't say anything, I feel terrible about this.
别担心 我嘴很严的
Oh, don't worry, I won't.
谢谢
Thanks.
"墙面专卖店的女人"? 别再抓着不放了!
"The woman at the wall store?" Let it go!
你要和Penny当面对质吗?
Are you going to confront Penny?
迟早是要的
Eventually, I guess.
但我我也有点好奇 她觉得她能在我
Although, I am kind of curious how long she thinks
没有发现的情况下把我的东西藏多久
she can keep hiding my stuff without me knowing.
这个嘛
Hmm.
与其和她们当面对质
You know, perhaps instead of confronting them,
我们应该看看她们要怎么使出瞬身解数
we should see how far they're willing to spin
来一个谎圆一个谎
their tangled webs.
就像那个之前在你桌子上的
Like that Spider-Man action figure
蜘蛛侠手办一样
that used to be on your desk.
天哪 我是瞎了吗?
Oh, my God, I'm going blind.
饭来咯
Hi. Food's here.
噢
Oh.
太棒了
Excellent.
我都饿坏了
I'm very hungry.
话说回来
Yeah, speaking of which,
你的公寓怎么样了?
what's going on with your apartment?
还在施工呢
Oh, uh, they're still working on it.
有意思
Interesting.
真有意思啊
Very interesting.
是啊 我们去饭店的路上顺道去看了下她的公寓
Yeah, we swung by her apartment on the way to the restaurant,
装修还需要一阵子
and they're gonna be fixing it for a while.
等等...你去看过她的公寓了?
Wait, uh... you saw her apartment?
我去了 还是一团乱
I did, still a mess.
- Leonard?  - 嗯?
- Leonard?  - Yeah?
我搞不懂了
Penny在说谎吗?
我不确定
你们...为什么要说克林贡语?
W...Why are you speaking Klingon?
那你为什么要说英语?
Why are you speaking English?
可笑
This is ridiculous.
Penny 你记得
Penny, do you remember
我教你的鸟语吗?
when I taught you Ubbi Dubbi?
当然记得
很好
Shledon是不是知道我在骗他?
如果Leonard告诉他
那可能就知道了
喂喂喂 停下来
Oh, wait, stop that.
要停下来的是你们
You stop that.
你听得懂她们说什么吗?
不懂
该死
好了好了
Okay.
够了
That's enough. You know what?
这是在干嘛?
What is going on?
好吧 我跟Sheldon说
Fine, I told Sheldon that
她的公寓已经装修好了
her apartment's been finished,
但刚刚你又说还没有
but then you just said it's not,
所以我现在懵逼了
so now I'm all confused.
Penny只是在帮我隐瞒
Penny was just covering for me.
我的房子两周前就弄好了
My place has been ready for two weeks.
你怎么可以骗我?
How could you lie to me?
她喜欢跟你住一起
Uh, she's enjoyed living with you.
这叫爱
It's called being in love.
那么
Mm-hmm, and what's it called
你偷偷搬走
when you secretly get rid
你老公的所有东西又叫什么?
of all your husband's stuff?
什么...没有的事!
Wha... That is not true!
什么没有... Bernadette告诉Howard Howard又告诉了我
Wh-wh-wh... Bernadette told Howard, Howard told me.
而且 我能看到我的东西都不见了!
Plus, I can see all my stuff is gone!
所以 你相信你朋友 你朋友的老婆
Oh, so, you believe your friend, and your friend's wife
还有你的眼睛 多过相信我咯?
and your own eyes over me?
哇
Wow.
你真的觉得我没有注意到
You really didn't think I'd notice
我的东西不见了吗?
my stuff was missing?
是吗 你看到你的钥匙环了吗?
Uh, did you notice your key chain?
蝙蝠侠哪去了?!
Where's Batman?!
嗨
Hey.
你为什么要告诉Howard
Why did you tell Howard
我把Leonard的东西藏起来了?
I was hiding Leonard's things?
等会
One sec.
你为什么要告诉Leonard
Why did you tell Leonard
我告诉了你Penny藏起了他的东西?!
I told you Penny was hiding his things?!
我只是顺口一说
It just came up
因为我们...我们讲秘密然后...
because we... we were talking about secrets and...
有谁是知道Amy公寓的事的?
等等
Wait.
你们都给我闭嘴!
Everybody stop it with that!
这真的不关我的事
I'm not really a part of this,
所以我还是先开吃了
so I'm just gonna dig in.
我不懂你为什么要把
And I'd like to know why you blabbed
我公寓的事说出去
about my apartment.
交给了你 大嘴巴
You're up, blabby.
Amy 对不起 我不该说出去的
Amy, I'm sorry, I shouldn't have said anything.
其实也没什么关系
I guess it's okay.
对不起
I'm sorry
公寓的事我骗了你
that I lied about my apartment.
没关系
It's all right.
然后...
And...
然后什么?
And what?
你的巫师袍是我下一个目标
Your wizard robes are next to go.
现在什么都说出来了
Now that everything's out on the table,
你们...你们觉得你们还会继续住在一起吗?
you...you think you two will keep living together?
虽然最近发生了这些事
Despite recent events,
但我认为我们的同居实验
I do consider our experiment
确实进展得挺顺利
in cohabitation to have been positive.
你是在说你愿意跟我住吗?
Are you saying you'd like to live with me?
我不排除这个可能性
I'm open to the possibility.
Amy 淡定
随便吧
Whatever.
哎 如果他以后都住对面了
You know, if he moves across the hall for good,
Leonard就可以把那些你不喜欢的东西
Leonard could keep the stuff you don't like
放在Shledon原来的房间了
in Sheldon's old room.
- 那问题就都解决了  - 好主意!
- Solves everything.  - That's a great idea!
哇 我可以把它改成游戏房
Ooh, maybe I could turn it into a gaming den.
太棒了
That would be amazing.
等等 等等 停一下 你们想干嘛?
Wait, wait, hold on, do what?
不好意思...那可是我的房间
Excuse me... that's my room.
但你以后不住这里了啊
But you won't be living here.
但那是我的房间
But that's my room.
- 但你以后不住这里了啊  - 但那是我的房间
- But you won't be living here.  - But that's my room.
你们可以开吃了
You guys might want to start eating.
但你以后不住这里了啊
But you won't be living here.
亲爱的 一旦你不再交房租
Sweetie, once you stop paying rent,
这些就全都不是你的
none of this is really yours.
但那是我的房间
But that's my room.
但你以后不住这里了!
But you won't be living here!
谢谢你的理解
Thank you for understanding.
哎 我懂的
Hey, I get it.
大家都想跟我待在一起
Everybody wants to spend more time with me.
我人见人爱 花见花开
I'm like a man made of sugar in a world of ants.
晚安
Good night.
好 晚安
Mm, night.
如果我们以后真的要继续住在一起
If we did continue living together,
还是住这里吗?
would it be here?
我不知道
I don't know.
有...有可能
It...it could be.
当然我们...
Of course there's...
我们也可以住你那边
there's always your apartment.
当...当然 我们可以住进我的公寓
S... Sure, sure, we... we could live in my apartment.
我讨厌你的公寓
I hate your apartment.
怪我咯 也是你先提的吧?
Sorry, you brought it up?
我觉得我们可以找一个新的地方
Well, I suppose we could find a whole new place.
而且 准确来说
You know, and, technically,
我们甚至不需要待在Pasadena
we don't even have to stay in Pasadena.
我们可以...可以搬去Altadena
We could...we could move to Altadena...
或者更远的地方
or a place that doesn't even end in "Dena."
听起来很爽
It's kind of exciting.
我们可以想干嘛就可以干嘛
I mean... we could do whatever we want.
但是如果我们搬家后
But what if we move
不喜欢那里呢?
and we don't like it?
如果楼里有个烟鬼呢?
What if there's a smoker in the building?
或者有宠物呢?
Or pets?
还有可能有霉菌
Or there could be mold.
那里也有可能会有交通噪音
There could be traffic noise.
我还得重新记下一条全新的公交线路
I'm gonna have to learn a whole new bus route.
你是在把"星际迷航"主题曲
Are you trying to soothe me
当摇篮曲唱 想安慰我吗?
by singing the Star Trek theme as a lullaby?
是的
Yes.
我又不是个孩子 别做这种事
I'm not a child, don't do that.
抱歉
Sorry.
你知道"2001太空漫游"吗?
Do you know 2001: A Space Odyssey?
这才对嘛 这才有安慰的感觉
All right, now that's soothing.
听着 我懂 这还是我的房间
Look, I... I get it, this is still my room;
我们还没有把它变成你的一部分
we haven't really made it yours.
谢谢
Thank you.
这也是为什么我给你
Which is why I got you
买了这个粉色的恐龙战队战士
this Pink Power Ranger.
你想把它放在哪儿都行
Put it anywhere you like.
好吧 但是你可能会有些不舒服哦
Okay, but you may feel some discomfort.
我开玩笑的啦 我希望你在这里有家的感觉
I'm kidding, I want you to feel at home here.
以任何你喜欢的方式来装饰这里吧
Decorate it any way that makes you happy.
你认真的吗?
Do you really mean that?
真的
I really do.
太好了 还有啦 你得知道
Great, and just so you know,
我也不是要把你所有的东西都弄走的
I'm not getting rid of all your stuff.
是吗? 那你准备留什么呢?
Yeah? What are you keeping?
那个蜡烛
That candle
还有你
and you.
那我的机器人海报呢?
What about my robot poster?
停 停 停 见好就收啊
Buh, buh, buh, buh, buh.
我最多只能忍那个蜡烛
I can make do with just the candle.
怎么啦?
What's going on?
我一想到要离开我的旧卧室就辗转反侧
I'm struggling with the thought of leaving my old bedroom.
那你能不能就心理转转啊?
Can it be more of an internal struggle?
我得看到它才行
I need to see it.
在我走开期间
While I'm gone,
别往我的枕头上呼气
don't breathe on my pillow.
要不我直接就不呼吸了怎么样啊?
How about if I just don't breathe at all?
这才是我的好姑娘
That's my girl.
什么鬼?
What on earth?
怎么回事?!
What is going on?!
哎哟 Sheldon
Oh, hey, Sheldon.
我们把你的房间
We turned your room
改成了一个嘿咻地牢
into a sex dungeon.
哦!
Oh!
不!
No!
怎么啦?!
What is happening?!
好了 最后一问
Okay, last question.
他当时穿的裤套...露臀的吗?
The chaps he was wearing... assless?
我们就不能专注于我现在面临的这个决定吗?
Can we just focus on the decision I'm facing?
行啊 不过讲真
We can, but for the record,
所有裤套都是露臀的
all chaps are assless.
裤套是指一般穿在裤子外面 只在腰部而非裆部连接的两个裤腿
先生们 拜托
Gentlemen, please,
这是个重要的决定啊
this is a significant decision.
Amy和我是不是要继续同居呢?
Now, do Amy and I continue living together?
还是我要回去再跟Lenard一起住?
Or do I move back in with Leonard?
跟我的露臀裤套一起啊
Over my assless chaps you will.
这不复杂啊
This isn't complicated.
你爱Amy吗?
Do you love Amy?
是的
Yes.
那你喜欢跟她同居吗?
Do you like living with her?
是的
Yes.
那你知道你现在要怎么做了吗?
Do you know what you need to do now?
很显然 我得自己想
Apparently, figure this out on my own
因为你们几个一点忙都帮不上
'cause you guys are no help at all.
嗨
Hi.
哈喽
Hello.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我只是在思考布里丹之驴
I'm just contemplating Buridan's donkey.
我懂了
I understand.
我会让你自己待着的
I'll leave you be.
什么 你知道这个典故吗?
What, you're familiar with the reference?
当然
Of course.
Jean Buridan提出了
Jean Buridan proposed
一个哲学理论 说
a philosophical thesis stating that
一只饥饿的驴被置于两堆同等距离的
a hungry donkey placed between two equidistant
干草堆的时候将会由于无法做出决定
bales of hay would be paralyzed by indecision
从而僵在原地 最终饿死
and would starve to death.
正是
Exactly.
那我不想让你饿死 所以...
Well, I wouldn't want you to starve to death, so...
...这有根茄子
...here's an eggplant.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道吗 有些人认为Buridan
You know, some people believe that Buridan
是窃取了亚里士多德的想法
was plagiarizing Aristotle.
真的吗?
Really?
不过
Although,
在亚里士多德的例子里
in Aristotle's example,
他提出的是一个饥饿和口渴程度相当的人
he proposed an equally hungry and thirsty man
陷在食物和饮品的两难之间
caught between food and drink.
这样啊
Huh.
是的 我在想这是不是跟
Yeah, I wonder if that's related
十二世纪的波斯哲学家
to the 12th century Persian philosopher,
Al-Ghazali有关
Al-Ghazali
他的故事是一个人
and his story of a man
在两个对象中间难以取舍
caught between two dates.
你是在说Al-Ghazali是亚里士多德学派的吗?
Are you suggesting Al-Ghazali was Aristotelian?
他可是反亚里士多德学派的
'Cause if anything, he was anti-Aristotelian.
Al-Ghazali是反亚里士多德学派的吗?
Al-Ghazali was anti-Aristotelian?
妈呀 还以为我了解他呢
Boy, you think you know a guy.
好了
Okay.
睁开眼睛看看你的新房间吧
Open your eyes and see your new room.
哇
Wow.
我...我知道我可能有点过了
I... I know I went a little overboard.
我们也还可以稍稍低调一点的啦
We can always dial it back.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no,
对...对我来说
it's... it's important to me
你拥有你想要的房间是很重要的
that you have the bedroom you want.
哦 这话太有意义了 我爱你
Oh, that means so much. I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我就在你的柜子里藏点东西 别告诉Penny
Just hiding some stuff in your closet, don't tell Penny.